it's not a secret there is one thing
that's going to separate those of you
who go on to become money-making Traders
and are consistently profitable from
those of you who joined the 95% that
unfortunately either completely give up
on trading blow their account or fail at
trading all together this one thing is a
strategy that you can stay consistent to
and that will make you money over time
and while this is not the only thing you
need to be a profitable Trader you will
never become a profitable Trader without
a money making strategy so in this video
what I want to do is break down a trade
I had on the New Zealand dollar along
with teach you the entire strategy that
I have used now for over 8 years to pull
profits out of the market and it has
been consistently profitable for me
throughout that whole time so if that
sounds good go a and click that like
button for me go a And subscribe if you
are new and I'll catch you after the
intro and
[Music]
disclaimer first off I'm going to go
through what a trading strategy is along
with why we need one and how to create
one for those of you who are brand new
then we'll dive into the entire rule set
for the whole strategy itself let's get
started with what is a trading strategy
a trading strategy is simply a method of
buying and selling based on a set of
predetermined rules that we use to make
trading decisions this strategy and set
of rules is just a fixed plan that we
use every time we step in the markets in
order to place trades I want you to
think of this as counting cards in
blackjack so in a casino the the casino
always has an edge even in the game of
blackjack the casino has an edge but
when you count cards in blackjack you
start to have an edge over the casino a
strategy for us does the same exact
thing and so just think of a strategy as
a set of rules that we use every time we
go into the markets in order to place
trades next up why do we need a trading
strategy the reason that you need a
trading strategy is because despite what
I personally thought whenever I started
trading me and you will never get to a
point where we can when 100% accurately
predict exactly what the Market's going
to do I'm not even kidding whenever I
first started trading I literally
thought that I would get so good at
trading that one day I'd be able to just
look at the market and I would know
exactly what it was going to do I
thought that I would become a wizard and
be able to tell the future for some
reason but that's not the case and
that's why we need a trading strategy
markets are slightly unpredictable so a
trading strategy gives us a rules-based
way to place trades that gives us a
money-making advantage over the market
and that's the way professional Traders
actually pull profits out of the market
it's not by being a wizard and knowing
what prices are going to do it's by
having a statistic Advantage based on a
rules-based trading strategy so that's
why you need to learn one as soon as
possible next up how do you create a
trading strategy well you create a
trading strategy using different
conditions that you look for each and
every time that you place a trade along
with a rules-based way that you actually
enter the market and a rules-based way
you place a stop-loss and a Target on a
specific trade all of these are
necessary so I use an acronym that I
call C if you've been a part of the
channel for a while you've definitely
heard of that but C stands for
conditions entries stops and targets and
so the set of rules we create using the
acronym C will be like our treasure map
to Buried Treasure and the buried
treasure is profits in our trading
account it'll again be like the rules
for counting cards except we're using
rules of a trading strategy in order to
gain an edge over the market now that
that's clear let me walk you through the
conditions that we're looking for with
this trading strategy first off this can
be traded on any time frame I personally
use the 4H hour chart now what we're
looking for with this strategy the first
initial condition is going to be a
market in Trend and when markets are
trending they tend to do something like
this pull back then break into new highs
and a lot of times instead of just
having this One Singular pullback we'll
see a situation of what I call and what
is considered accumulation
so we'll see prices start to consolidate
after our impulsive move and then
eventually throughout this consolidation
we'll see prices break above the
previous swing high that was the highest
point of this consolidation so this is
what we're looking for with this
strategy the initial thing we want to
see is that price is in Trend the way
we're going to do that is we're going to
use a 50 EMA so just assume that this is
the 50 EMA and what we're going to do is
as long as price is trading above the 50
EMA we're going to say that's an uptrend
after we see an uptrend price is
consistently making higher highs and
higher lows as well we want to see this
period of accumulation that looks like
this after we see price break above that
while in an uptrend we're going to be
looking for a pullback into this top
layer of that accumulation phase this is
going to be the conditions we need to
see before we go and look for an actual
entry reason these are the conditions of
the strategy for a bullish trade so to
break that down one more time we want to
see the market in Trend meaning making
new higher highs compared to the
previous highs and new higher lows right
here compared to our previous lows we
also want to see all this happening
above the 50 EMA we want to see a phase
of accumulation which is going to be
defined as we want to see a swing high
that is tested at least twice it can be
tested more than twice but we want to
see it tested at least twice before the
break through that in continuation in
this uptrend now after we see that we
want to see a pull back into the top
layer of this accumulation or back into
that previous resistance area and those
are the conditions for a bullish entry
we'll move on to the entry reason right
after I go through a bearish example of
this right now in a bearish version of
this trade we would want to see prices
pushing lower and then we would want to
see what we would want to see a period
of accumulation this is accumulation of
sell Traders traders that are looking to
sell the market after this period of
accumulation that would be right in this
area we would like to see price push
back up to this area right here and all
this needs to happen under what moving
average that would be the 50 EMA right
so we want to see all this happening
below the 50 EMA once we have prices in
a downtrend below the 50 EMA and we have
a period of accumulation where a support
level has been tested multiple times and
we get a pullback into that level then
we have have all our conditions met and
at that point we can look for an entry
reason and something that makes this
even more powerful is if this level has
been tested in the past throughout a
bigger period of consolidation so
something like this would be an example
of that we would have this level tested
multiple times back here in a period of
consolidation then we have this
downtrend below the 50 EMA then we have
the accumulation period followed by the
breakout of that accumulation period
period and the pullback into it with
that being the case we're going to go
down some real charts now take a look at
a real example of this on a trade I had
on the New Zealand dollar and I'm going
to share the entry reason stops and
targets that I personally use for this
exact trading strategy so let's take a
look based on what you just learned
about a bearish version of this strategy
this is a bearish trade would we have
all of the conditions met where price is
right now where I just
circled hopefully you were able to say
yes and here's the reason we have price
is doing what this is the 50 EMA by the
way we have prices pushing below the 50
EMA we have this pullback we have what
we consider an area of accumulation
right here we then have a break through
that area of accumulation and a pullback
that comes right back into it so to draw
this out the way we would be looking at
this is right at this area of
accumulation after we have price
breaking through it I would mark off my
zone of accumulation like this and at
that point I would be waiting for price
to push back up into that zone we've
already broken through it so now that
we've broken through it all the
conditions except a pullback into this
Zone have been met so in this case our
little area of accumulation was buyers
trying to step in sellers taking back
control buyers trying to step in again
creating our one two tests of this area
of accumulation and then sellers taking
over completely and continuing this
downtrend so now the only thing left to
do is wait to see if we get a pullback
into this zone now what do we have have
right here we have a pullback that comes
up and actually touches our Zone with
this Wick so this is exactly what we're
looking for in terms of conditions we
have our downtrend we are still below
the 50 EMA we're even kind of pushing
off the 50 EMA giving some added
Confluence to help our trade out even
further and now that we're here we have
remember the acronym all of C taken care
of C is conditions all of our conditions
are taken care of now we move on to the
next step in that acronym for this
strategy which is what are we going to
use as an entry so for this specific
strategy I use Simple Candlestick and
chart patterns I'm looking for simple
Candlestick patterns or a simple chart
pattern meaning in this area I'm looking
for selling pressure for a bearish trade
what would selling pressure look like
well it would look something like this
big red candle as soon as I see this big
red candle come into play after all my
other conditions are met the close of
this candle is when I actually press the
sell button this is going to be my entry
so now what do we have now we have the
conditions met for this entire strategy
for a bearish trade we now have an entry
in place because our entry was met after
all our confluences were met as well the
next step in our
CEST process is finding a place for
stops and finding a place for our Target
now two things I want to share before we
talk about the stops and targets first
off this was actually an even more
accurate trading opportunity because of
the fact what did I say earlier remember
the added Confluence of having this be a
level that was a previous level of
consolidation already well this is a
level that was it had already been
tested multiple times in the past then
we also ended up getting all the
Confluence that we needed all of the
conditions for this exact strategy here
with this downtrend accumulation
breakout and pullback so that added even
more Confluence to this specific trade
also this is a trade I took and shared
with all the members of the TTC forx
University you can see that right over
here and this is something I share with
them two to five times a week depending
on how many trades I end up getting
based on the strategies they're learning
inside of the University if you'd like
access to all that plus you'd like to
get these emails two to five times a
week all you got to do is click the top
Link in the description or go to
www.tcf university.com if not no big
deal at all let's go ahead and move on
to stops and targets on this specific
trade and for this entire strategy that
I use So I entered the trade based on
this entry candle and for a stop loss I
just use something called the ATR
indicator it's easily found all you got
to do is go to your indicators on
whatever platform you use type in
average true range and it should be one
of the top ones that pops up so the
average true range gives you an average
of the last 14 candles on the chart so
this stop-loss placement keeps me in
line with the volatility of the market
and the volatility of the pair that I'm
trading so with this being the case in
the top left of my screen you can see
this is 20 Pips we discount that last
number so right now the ATR is 20 Pips
what that means for my stop loss is I'm
going to go 20 Pips above this swing
high so up to that swing high is about
24 Pips if I add 20 to that my stop loss
will be 44 Pips so that's how I place
the stop loss for this strategy and now
we have c e and s taken care of the last
thing we need to do is find a spot to
take our Target now this part of my
trading is one of the only parts that's
mostly subjective not objective if if
you've noticed I have rules for
everything for my target I have rules
but they're not as set in stone as the
rules for everything else I like to get
as much as I can out of the market and
specifically in this case all I did was
look left for structure in order to take
these targets I went out to a daily time
frame as a matter of fact and I also
looked here at the next level we would
hit that's been tested multiple times I
got about a 1.9 to1 reward to risk ratio
out of this bad boy here so my targets
were actually a little bit lower right
in that area again just based on this
next level of support that's been
resistance before so for targets for me
at least I use structure looking left
the next level specifically I use the
next level price will inevitably hit if
we continue this downtrend and if we go
back over to the 4our chart and I click
play for you pause that let me actually
just go over to a real time chart of the
New Zealand dollar you'll see this trade
right here this is the chart I actually
placed it on I used a different chart to
do the tutorial because I have this one
marked up but as you can see we do in
fact go down enough to hit those 1.9 to1
Targets on this trade so we started with
a bearish version of this strategy why
don't we take a look at a bullish
version now for a bullish example now I
want you to take a look at the chart and
tell me do you think there's something
you should be paying attention to at
this moment where price is right
now hopefully you were able to say yes
and here's the reason we have price
pushing up going above the 50 EMA we
then have a pullback an area of
accumulation why is this considered an
area of accumulation because it's been
tested multiple times within this
pullback so we have one two we call this
three tests before the pullback here and
the break above now that we've had this
breakout after having a trending move
above the 50 EMA what are we doing now
now we are going going to create a zone
at the top of our area of accumulation
which would be right there and if we
want some extra added confirmation we
can look left and if we look left what
do we see we see that this is in fact an
area that's been tested also recently in
the past along with being an area of
accum accumulation right now before the
breakout so now that we have all of
these factors together the next thing
we're looking for after our accumulation
that word's getting harder to say
throughout the video the next thing
we're going to be looking for is price
to push higher and eventually pull back
to this Zone that's the only other thing
we need for our conditions to be met
let's see what price does eventually
price does this where it does in fact
pull back to that area of accumulation
at this point do we have all of the
conditions met in our acronym
CEST yes so our conditions are checked
off what's the next thing we're going to
be looking for it's our actual entry and
what are we using for that it's just
going to be buying pressure either a
specific Candlestick pattern like an
engulfing a close above a big green
candle would be completely fine or some
type of chart pattern maybe we end up
getting a little double bottom right in
this area before prices push higher both
of those entries would be fine in my
standards or at least for my specific
way of trading this strategy so that's
what we're looking for for e or for
entry let's see what we get and voila
that would be a close above green candle
a big green candle that would be what we
consider buying pressure after all of
our conditions are met be aware of this
we're not just trading based on a
Candlestick pattern if you go out just
trying to trade based on a single
Candlestick pattern you're going to lose
money we're waiting for all of these
factors to align a very specific set of
rules just like people that count cards
in blackjack have a very specific set of
rules they use in order to gain an edge
over the casino we are using a very
specific set of rules to gain an edge
over the market and instead of being The
Gambler we become the casino by doing so
so in this case we have our entry right
there do you remember what the stops and
targets were when we're looking for stop
losses remember the only thing I'm using
is the ATR indicator which gives me the
average of the last 14 candles at the
point of this candle if we look up here
to the left we have a 31 pip remember we
discount that last number we have a 31
pip ATR so with that being the case
we're going to go or I'm going to go
excuse me 31 Pips below my swing low
right there that red candle down to that
swing low we have 45 so we add 31 to
that we end up with a 76 pip stoploss
after that 76 pip stop- loss in order to
find a Target I'm going to look left and
see where's the next level of structure
price is going to hit and to me it looks
like about this area due to the fact
that we have support resistance support
resistance so this is going to be and by
the way I'm going to be managing the
position up to this area but that's
going to be about where I decided to
take targets right at around a 1.9 to1
reward to risk ratio on this specific
trade let's hit play and see how this
specific trade would have worked out as
you can see the market eventually pushes
up high enough to in fact hit those
targets one thing I want to make very
clear and I want you to keep in mind is
that you're not going to win every
single trade that you place just like if
a player is counting cards in blackjack
they're not going to win every single
hand they have an advantage that plays
out over a long sample size of hands
they play for us it's over a long sample
size of Trades we place that's when our
advantage plays out you're not going to
be 100% accurate with any trading
strategy that you use so just because
all I showed was winning examples don't
take that as this strategy only wins it
wins and it loses and for my testing and
trading it gives me around a 60%
accuracy with whatever Target I use as
long as I'm using structure for my
targets which is an unbelievable Edge
over the market when it plays out over a
large sample size of Trades so now
you've got the strategy down but wait
there's more a strategy by itself is not
going to make you a profitable Trader
even if it is in fact a strategy that
gives an edge over the market your
emotions and your risk management are
going to play a major role in your
ability to become a profitable Trader
let me do a visual example of this to
make it more clear so I call this the
triangle of trading success in the
middle of this triangle is all the
traders that are currently making money
on the outside is everyone that's losing
and the reason everyone on the outside
is not making money is because they
haven't mastered these three skills the
first one we just worked on that's a
strategy that has a proven Edge that
will make you money if you stay
consistent to it over time that's the
first part of this it needs to be
rules-based so you can actually follow
it and stay consistent to it and it
needs to be profitable over time so that
it actually makes you money the next
skill profitable Traders have mastered
and non-profitable Traders have not is
risk management go into any trading
environment whether you're trading in
stocks crypto Forex like me whatever it
may be go into it understanding that
there is a very high likelihood that you
will be losing a lot of Trades what do I
mean by that think about a 55 or a 60%
accurate strategy that means 40 out of
every 100 trades if you have a 60%
accuracy that you place you will lose
you're going to have losing trades what
we do in order to handle our promotions
and keep those losing trades from
blowing our account or making us lose a
lot more than we're comfortable with is
we manage risk correctly as professional
Traders we're not out here trying to
gamble our way to getting rich as fast
as possible if that's what you want to
do with your money obviously it's
completely up to you you can do whatever
you want to I'm just telling you how
professional Traders go about placing
trades we don't do it with a 10 20 30%
risk on every every trade because that's
a great way to become emotional about
your trades also a great way to blow
your account very quickly we do it with
a very small risk per trade and although
we have a small risk per trade as long
as we have an edge over the market that
plays out over a long period of time we
will make money consistently so managing
risk is super important there's three
different types of managing risk the
first is going to be what I call your
risk Capital this is the amount of money
based on your net worth that you're
comfortable trading with you're not
going to be Trad or I guess you can
again your money do what you want to
with it but I would never put 100% of my
life savings into a speculative trading
account like swing trading or day
trading in Forex it just does it's
really risky so it doesn't make sense to
risk everything you have on that now
what you can do is break it up and go
I'm going to risk a certain percent of
my net worth on Forex and that
percentage is going to be whatever makes
you comfortable could be 10 20 30 40 50%
of all the money you have that's
completely completely up to you the
second part of risk management is going
to be risk per trade every time you
place a trade how much are you risking
on that trade for me it's between 1 and
2% it's going to be different for
everyone and the third part of risk
management is what I call overall risk
exposure what this means is how many
trades can you be in at once if I'm
risking 2% per trade and I only want to
have an overall risk exposure of 10%
that means I can only be in five trades
at once if you'll come up with a number
that will keep you comfortable for all
of those a comfortable risk capital a
comfortable risk per trade and a
comfortable overall exposure then you'll
have risk management down and that's how
you do it after having risk management
down the third thing that separates
profitable Traders from people that are
still struggling from people that will
either completely give up completely
fail blow their accounts is going to be
trading psychology so if you don't have
a good trading mindset which is highly
affected by the way by your risk
management and your strategy but trading
psychology is something that you must
Master as well you have to understand
losses are a part of trading and you
have to be able to control your emotions
without making silly mistakes when those
losses occur you can't switch strategies
once a week and expect to ever be
profitable I know there's some of you
out there doing that comment below if
it's you don't worry you're not alone I
did it to at the beginning of my career
I'm just trying to save you the
heartache that I went through before
realizing trading psychology is an
extremely important part of becoming a
professional and profitable Trader now
if you want help with all three of these
we do go through this in a very
organized way throughout the TTC forx
University again that also comes with
email analysis like New Zealand dollar
that you saw earlier today and it comes
with priority email support which means
I will be the one answering any trading
related questions that you have we also
have a 30-day money back guarantee on
the University so if you're interested
in that top Link in the description or
you can go to
www.tcf university.com if you're not
interested in that no worries at all
make sure to click the like button if
you enjoyed the video and learned
something comment below if you made it
to the end subscribe if you're new and
I'll catch you in the next video see you
soon